<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Billy Mobile | Programming Rambling]]></title>
  <link href="http://mrzard.github.com/blog/categories/billy-mobile/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mrzard.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-03-02T07:26:17+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://mrzard.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Gonzalo Míguez]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Becoming a dadveloper]]></title>
    <link href="http://mrzard.github.com/blog/2017/03/01/becoming-a-dadveloper/"/>
    <updated>2017-03-01T18:54:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://mrzard.github.com/blog/2017/03/01/becoming-a-dadveloper</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So... this is awkward... It's been almost two years without any new content on
this blog. I will do something useful in this 4 hour flight from Helsinki to
Barcelona, and I will try to write some things about what has been going on
with me for those two years.</p>

<p>2015-2016 at <a href="http://www.billymob.com">Billy Mobile</a> were intense and
exciting years . I had the immense luck to start working with some amazing
people like <a href="https://es.linkedin.com/in/diego-frison-715279b1">Diego Frisón</a>,
<a href="https://es.linkedin.com/in/joanviladrosa">Joan Viladrosa</a>,
<a href="https://es.linkedin.com/in/rogerrafanell">Roger Rafanell</a>,
<a href="https://es.linkedin.com/in/adayrobaina">Aday Robaina</a>,
<a href="https://es.linkedin.com/in/ibruque">Ivan Bruque</a>,
<a href="https://es.linkedin.com/in/davideferrari">Davide Ferrari</a>,
<a href="https://es.linkedin.com/in/enric-sardina-marti-97717217">Enric Sardina</a>,
<a href="https://es.linkedin.com/in/ginesortiz">Ginés Ortiz</a>,
<a href="https://es.linkedin.com/in/oriolblanc">Oriol Blanc</a>,
<a href="https://es.linkedin.com/in/marc-rubia-criado-94a9a458">Marc Rubia</a>,
<a href="https://es.linkedin.com/in/david-llorente-garrido-001552a1">David Llorente</a>,
<a href="https://es.linkedin.com/in/slissner">Sam Lissner</a>,
<a href="https://es.linkedin.com/in/jonatan-fernandez-389aa271">Jonatan Fernández</a> or
<a href="https://es.linkedin.com/in/aserrabl">Alex Serra</a>,
as well as keep working with other great people like Oriol Orellana or
Horacio Herrera, whom I have talked about in the past. And that is only
counting people on the Tech Team at Billy. They are all top notch talent,
and only great things are ahead of them.</p>

<p>With Joan's leadership, the PHP-MySQL-Redis-ElasticSearch Billy adserver
prototype was ported to Java-Kafka-HBase-Spark-Redis-HDFS which made a lot more
sense as to deal with the concurrency and speed needed. He even introduced some
very cool and cutting edge technology like Apache Kylin. At the same time all
of these cool changes were happening, I started realizing that my daughter
needed for me to devote more time to her. And I also started realizing that <em>I</em>
needed to devote more time to her. The fine people at Billy Mobile tried to
work out a semi-remote schedule with me, but it was not the best fit to have
one of the Tech Leads away for a big part of the day, which shifted a lot of
work onto Joan's shoulders, and ended up making obvious that a change had to
be made. So after having the luck of being contacted by
<a href="http://www.dealdash.com">DealDash</a>, it was a golden opportunity for me and
I decided to say goodbye to Billy. I will always be grateful for their support
and effort to help me out, and for the chance to work and learn with so many
amazing people.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.dealdash.com">DealDash</a> offered me the opportunity to get back into
a developer position and also start working remotely. The company is based in
Helsinki, and the remote philosophy allows me to do these kinds of things:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Take a couple of hours off to bring Ada to the park, or dancing, or to the
toy library. Then either wake up early and work before the daily meeting, or
do it before going to bed at night.</p></li>
<li><p>Stop worrying about the added commute time to and from the office, specially
if I also happened to have to bring Ada to the doctor's. That used to mean
almost a "lost" day when I was working in the office, now it's just a minor
adjustment and no work is lost.</p></li>
<li><p>When I sit to work I just check Slack and the GitHub issues to see what
progress has been made so I can pick up like I were there when it happened.</p></li>
<li><p>If Ada's mom needs to go to the doctor or run any errands, it's a lot easier
for her as she can just leave Ada with me. I just pick up smaller stuff or
bring her to a cafe that has toys where she can play in a new environment
while I keep working.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>I think I break most of the 'rules' of working remotely, as other than fixed
meetings (Grooming, Retrospectives, Sprint Planning, Daily standup), I tend to
bend my hours to whichever happens that day. It's working out for me, and at
the same time I can see that it's not for everyone.
But there is a method to my chaos.</p>

<p>At DealDash I have found another amazing team and while I am still learning a
lot about the business of penny auctions, we have already started on the path
of improving and refactoring a lot of functionality. I have been with them for
a little bit over 4 months now and I already have had the chance to try some
new things (for me) like Docker, provisioning machines with Salt, some NodeJS,
using Gherkin to describe the behavior of functionalities and couple that with
unit and/or functional tests and also pick up Symfony again.</p>

<p>DealDash is also teaching me a great deal on how to make a remote team work,
how to keep your team in touch with your users' needs and how to encourage and
foster an open communication style where everyone knows their voices matter.</p>

<p>So what more can I ask for? I am working with once again on an amazing team, on
interesting problems, I am learning new stuff AND I have all the time I need to
devote to my daughter: right now I am heading back to Barcelona from the first
team offsite with DealDash, which I had to cut short because Ada had an
accident. And they were again supportive and understanding.</p>

<p>So this is my new life. I have become a <em>dadveloper</em>.</p>

<p><em>And I could not be happier</em>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Billy is hiring! Middleweight PHP developer needed]]></title>
    <link href="http://mrzard.github.com/blog/2014/08/20/billy-is-hiring-middleweight-php-developer-needed/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-20T10:52:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://mrzard.github.com/blog/2014/08/20/billy-is-hiring-middleweight-php-developer-needed</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As most of you know, since June 2nd I've taken the position of MVAS IT Manager at <a href="http://www.billymob.com">Billy Mobile</a>.</p>

<p>Well, the family is growing, and I need a pair of hands on my side.</p>

<p>Right now we are using some Symfony components (HttpFoundation, DependencyInjection, Configuration, Router, EventDispatcher, Console and Templating) and we are creating a lot of libraries for our own use which we control with Composer / Satis. We also are going to possibly include node.js in some of our apps.</p>

<p>Your job will be connecting our apps with 3rd party APIs, creating new libraries that connect us to different services, thinking of how to improve our metrics and having fun while doing so. We have three different areas were you can make impact (mobile web apps, a very custom adserver and a REST-ish API for native mobile apps).</p>

<p>We are looking for:</p>

<ul>
<li><p> A fun person to be around</p></li>
<li><p> All-around nice person</p></li>
<li><p> Middleweight PHP developer. You have some experience, but want to improve and / or take on new challenges. Or maybe you have a ton of experience, and you like this job posting!</p></li>
<li><p> Comfortable with MySQL (queries, indexes, joins...)</p></li>
<li><p> Comfortable with the Mediator pattern and design patterns in general</p></li>
<li><p> Comfortable with git and composer</p></li>
<li><p> Understands Dependency Injection</p></li>
<li><p> Can document code, or writes code so beautiful it's auto-commented (if this is you please teach me).</p></li>
<li><p> Maybe has a bit (or a lot) of experience with testing.</p></li>
<li><p> Maybe has experience with key-value stores (Redis, Memcached or other), and NoSQL solutions (MongoDB, CouchDB, ElasticSearch or other...)</p></li>
<li><p> <em>Strong english skills required</em> - this a must, as we are an international company that need to communicate clearly in English with both coworkers and partners.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>We are offering:</p>

<ul>
<li><p> Good salary and company perks</p></li>
<li><p> An environment were prototyping, putting your ideas out there and trying new stuff is encouraged</p></li>
<li><p> Lots of growth opportunities</p></li>
<li><p> The chance to impact a working business model</p></li>
<li><p> Working with yours truly which is AWESOME</p></li>
<li><p> Free coffee and soft drinks</p></li>
<li><p> Great coworkers</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Do you think you want this job? Then drop me an email at my name at billymob.com or <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/jobs2/view/11081010?trk=biz-overview-job-post">apply on LinkedIn</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
