<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: other ramblings | Programming Rambling]]></title>
  <link href="http://mrzard.github.com/blog/categories/other-ramblings/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mrzard.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-03-25T13:25:33+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://mrzard.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Gonzalo Míguez]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Common recruiting errors made by companies.]]></title>
    <link href="http://mrzard.github.com/blog/2011/12/14/common-recruiting-errors-made-by-companies/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-14T10:26:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://mrzard.github.com/blog/2011/12/14/common-recruiting-errors-made-by-companies</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Lately I've seen a lot of posts about errors candidates make in interviews.
Now I am going to write a list of error employers make when looking for candidates.</p>

<p>1 - Adding them in LinkedIn without asking or even introducing themselves.</p>

<p>Guys,we get it, you are important. Now, please, the thing is YOU came looking
for us, not the other way around. Introduce yourself. Why are you adding me
as a contact? Keep in mind we do not know each other. For me this is the professional
equivalent to "hey, wanna hook up?" in a dating site.</p>

<p>2 - Recruting agencies special: Not disclosing which company they are recruiting
for</p>

<p>Yes, I can understand you want to be discreet and everything, but again, you
came looking for a candidate. Do you really expect a (hopefully) talented person
to engage in a (possibly) lengthy selection process when they know nothing
about their employer?</p>

<p>3 - Not stating salary / compensation</p>

<p>If you are out there looking for talent, that talent is most of the time already
employed. Why waste your time and the candidate's time by making him/her go
to interviews just to know the salary bracket? Also, even for unemployed talent,
they will be drawn to the offers that give the most information. Hiding this
crucial piece of info makes no sense to me.</p>

<p>4 - Keeping a <code>you're _sooooo_ lucky</code> attitude</p>

<p>Yes, we are lucky because most of us love our jobs. That's it. You came looking
for us, not the other way around, this is a key concept.<strong> You are the lucky
ones if we are the top-notch employees you are looking for:</strong> <strong>we make more
money for you than from you</strong>.</p>

<p>5 - Not having tech people at the interview</p>

<p>Personal interviews are fine, but we usually want to discuss details. Which
technologies are we going to use? How many users? How many people are on the
team? Is there a lot of turnover? Do we have a VPN so we can work remotely?
Frameworks? And these are just basic questions most of the time HR cannot answer.
Please, please, please, have a tech person there.</p>

<p>Have I left something out? (Pretty sure I have). Don't hesitate to comment
and expand this list :D</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Two Things about Computer Programming (by Charles Miller)]]></title>
    <link href="http://mrzard.github.com/blog/2010/11/14/the-two-things-about-computer-programming-by/"/>
    <updated>2010-11-14T16:30:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://mrzard.github.com/blog/2010/11/14/the-two-things-about-computer-programming-by</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://fishbowl.pastiche.org/2007/04/15/the_two_things_about_computer_programming/">This article</a> by Charles Miller says there are only two things that are
<strong>really important</strong> to any discipline. This may or may not be true, but I
really think he nailed it when it comes to programming.</p>

<blockquote><p><strong>Computer Programming:</strong></p>

<ol>
<li>Every problem can be solved by breaking it up into a series of smaller problems.</li>
<li>The computer will always do exactly what you tell it to.</li>
</ol>


<p><strong>Software Engineering:</strong></p>

<ol>
<li>Writing the code is the easy part. Writing it so someone else can understand it later is the important part.</li>
<li>Make it work, then make it elegant, then make it fast.</li>
</ol>
</blockquote>

<p>It's very nice to see there are people out there who can summarize things in
such a comprehensive and spot-on manner.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[WebP, The New Google Image Format]]></title>
    <link href="http://mrzard.github.com/blog/2010/10/01/webp-the-new-google-image-format/"/>
    <updated>2010-10-01T09:44:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://mrzard.github.com/blog/2010/10/01/webp-the-new-google-image-format</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>WebP is the new format Google is pushing to come to the rescue of broadband
usage and get the place now JPEG holds. Tests seem to put WebP ahead of JPEG
by a 39% file size margin, while holding at least as much quality as an equivalent
JPEG. The format is lossy, as JPEG is, but seems to achieve better quality
with less file size.</p>

<p>Google says they expect to get better compression percentages when starting
from an uncompressed file rather than an already compressed one. I really want
to see this at work, but again, people are VERY used to JPEGs by now, and in
a broadband world, 100kB vs 61kB is not a big deal. Now, if you're downloading
100's of images, that could very well make a big impact, but that's not the
case with a very big portion of users.</p>

<p>Nevertheless, Google again shows they are concerned with making the web lighter,
faster and easier, and I will be keeping an eye out for this new format.</p>

<p>More info at Google Code Blog on: <a href="http://googlecode.blogspot.com/2010/09/webp-new-image-format-for-web.html">WebP, a new image format for the web</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lagoa, a breathtaking physics engine]]></title>
    <link href="http://mrzard.github.com/blog/2010/07/21/lagoa-a-breathtaking-physics-engine/"/>
    <updated>2010-07-21T12:52:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://mrzard.github.com/blog/2010/07/21/lagoa-a-breathtaking-physics-engine</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=13457383&amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;show_title=1&amp;show_byline=1&amp;show_portrait=0&amp;color=&amp;fullscreen=1"></a></p>

<p><a href="http://vimeo.com/13457383">Lagoa Multiphysics 1.0 - Teaser</a> from <a href="http://vimeo.com/thiagocosta">Thiago Costa</a> on <a href="http://vimeo.com">Vimeo</a>.</p>

<p>There's little information about this physics engine, other than it looks awesome.
Original website: <a href="http://lagoatechnologies.com/">http://lagoatechnologies.com/</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tumblr: 6M users, 1,500M monthly pageviews (from 255M a year ago)]]></title>
    <link href="http://mrzard.github.com/blog/2010/07/21/tumblr-6m-users-1500m-monthly-pageviews-from/"/>
    <updated>2010-07-21T12:40:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://mrzard.github.com/blog/2010/07/21/tumblr-6m-users-1500m-monthly-pageviews-from</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Via techcrunch, an overview of the impressive growth sprout that Tumblr has
had.</p>

<p><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2010/07/19/tumblr-stats/">http://techcrunch.com/2010/07/19/tumblr-stats/</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
